Guide to The Billie Jean King Collection 1901-2019 (bulk, 1940-2019) MS 3147
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Speeches, 2002-2019; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  - Cal State LA, 2007 October 6 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 54)
    Contains schedule of events, schedule of speakers, and BJK's typed remarks for the BJK and Friends, Presenting the Joe Shapiro Award event. Topics of remarks include history of the event, student-athlete scholarships, and legacy.
  - Merrill Lynch: Achieving Life, 2007 October 11 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 55)
    Contains event schedule, fact sheet, and prepared questions for a conversation with BJK.
  - Women's Sports Foundation annual dinner, 2007 October 15 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 56)
    Contains event program, schedule, and BJK's typed remarks welcoming audience to event and speaking on the Women's Sports Foundation.
  - Hillary Women's Finance Summit, 2007 October 17 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 57)
    Contains correspondence and typed BJK talking points for Hillary Clinton event, National Women's Finance Council Summit. Topics of remarks include BJK's endorsement of HRC, Title IX, and leadership.
  - Public Justice Foundation, 2007 October 18 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 58)
    Contains Public Justice twenty-five year report, correspondence, event program, and BJK's typed remarks with handwritten edits. Topics of remarks include Title IX and responsibility for change.
  - YWCA of Silicon Valley, 2007 October 23 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 59)
    Contains corerspondence and BJK's typed notes for remarks with handwritten edits. Topics of remarks include the mission and programs of the YWCA, history of the YWCA, living one's truth, accepting responsibility, and BJK's personal and professional milestones.
  - Hillary Clinton campaign Nevada, 2007 October 27 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 60)
    Contains memos and BJK's schedule for Nevada visit on behalf of the HRC campaign.
  - UBS All Bar None, 2007 October 30 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 61)
    Contains itinerary, service agreement, and suggested questions for BJK interview at UBS Women's event.
  - Hillary Clinton campaign dinner, 2007 November 10 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 62)
    Contains correspondence, event program, and background information for the Iowa Democratic Party's 2007 Jefferson Jackson Dinner.
  - Mannington Mills Stand on a Better World Awards, 2007 November 15 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 1)
    Contains correspondence, event background documents, and BJK's typed remarks with handwritten additions. Topics of remarks include Mannington Mills' company values, congratulations to award winners, and introduction of award recipient Debra Bonde.
  - London Times Sportswoman of the Year, 2007 November 20 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 2)
    Contains event program, itinerary, and BJK's typed and handwritten remarks for congratulating recipients of the awards.
  - Women's Sports Foundation, 2007 November 27 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 3)
    Contains press conference itinerary and BJK's typed remarks for Women's Sports Foundation GoGirlGo! Boston events.
  - March of Dimes Sports Luncheon, 2007 November 28 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 4)
    Contains event program, schedule, and BJK's typed and handwritten remarks for presentation of award to Lindsay Davenport.
  - Fox Chase Cancer Center, 2007 November 28 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 5)
    Contains event schedule, flier, and printed webpages.
  - Hillary Clinton National Winter Summit, 2007 December 14 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 6)
    Contains event itinerary and BJK's typed remarks in support of the HRC campaign.
  - Hillary Clinton New Hampshire, 2008 January 7 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 7)
    Contains typed schedules, memos, itineraries for HRC campaign events in New Hampshire.
  - Arthur Ashe Institute for Urban Health gala, 2008 April 24 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 8)
    Contains event program and BJK's typed and handwritten remarks on memories of Arthur Ashe and the Institute for Urban Health.
  - Fortune Most Powerful Women, 2008 May 22 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 9)
    Contains printed email correspondence and BJK's typed remarks on mentorship.
  - LPGA, 2009 May 1-3 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 10)
    Contains event itinerary and BJK's typed remarks on women's sports.
  - Cal State LA Board of Trustees, 2015 November 18 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 11)
    Contains BJK's typed remarks with handwritten edits for Board of Trustees presentation on the naming of the Rosie Casals and Pancho Gonzalez Tennis Center at the BJK Sports Complex.
  - Athlete Ally Action Awards, 2018 October 6 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 12)
    Contains event program and BJK's notes for remarks on the fight for equality.
  - BBC Spotty Awards, 2018 December 16 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 13)
    Contains BJK's typed and handwritten notes for acceptance of the BBC Sports Lifetime Achievement Award.
  - RBG documentary screening introductory remarks, 2019 January 11 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 10)
  - USTA Pride, 2019 August 22 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 14)
    Contains BJK's itinerary for the US Open 2019, including USTA Pride panel with prepared questions for BJK, and BJK's handwritten notes prepared for panel.
  - USTA president and chairman, 2019 August 26 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 15)
    Contains BJK's typed remarks for introducing Patrick Galbraith as the new Chairman of the Board and President of the USTA.
  - Althea Gibson statue unveiling, 2019 August 26 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 16)
    Contains BJK's typed and handwritten remarks on Althea Gibson.
  - CityParks Foundation, 2019 August 27 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 17)
    Contains event program and BJK's typed talking points from the 2019 CityParks Tennis Benefit. Topics of remarks include the importance of public parks. fundraising, and the CityParks community service initiatives.
- Series V. Awards and recognition, 1956-2019; 4.5 Linear feet in 1 carton and 2 flat boxes
  Series V contains certificates, awards, and documents of recognition presented to BJK throughout her life, including in the course of her tennis career and beyond. Document types include awarded certificates, related event programs, and letters of recognition. Each award file may include only the certificate itself or only related documents. Award types include official tennis ranking certificates, honorary degrees, and commemorative proclamations, reflecting BJK's varied achievements and prominence of BJK's influence.
  - United States National Parks Eighth Annual Junior Tennis Championships, 1956 July 30-August 5 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 54)
  - United States Lawn Tennis Association ranking certificates, 1959-1966 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 18)
  - Long Beach Century Club Sports Night Awards, 1963-1968, 1989 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 19)
  - City of Long Beach resolutions, 1966-1973 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 20)
  - Alhambra, CA Tribute to BJK, 1966 September 18 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 21)
  - All-Sports Almanac Athletes of the Year, 1967 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 22)
  - Associated Press Athlete of the Year, 1967 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 23)
  - California Legislature Resolutions, 1968, 1987 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 1)
  - BJK Tennis Center Long Beach, 1968 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 24)
  - Billie Jean Moffitt King Day, 1968 September 13 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 25)
  - City of Manhattan Beach Resolution of Commendation, 1968 November 23 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2, Item 8)
  - Conference on Physical Fitness and Sports appointment, 1970 September 25 (Offsite-box 60, Folder 4)
    Certificate signed by President Richard Nixon.
  - Sports Illustrated Sportswoman of the Year, 1972 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 1)
  - Commonwealth of Massachusetts BJK Day, 1983 March 19 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - Los Angeles Olympic Organizing Committee certificate, 1984 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - Women's International Center Living Legacy Award, 1984 March 1 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 26)
  - Honorary Citizen of Tucson, Arizona, 1984 November 7 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 27)
  - Cal State L.A. Athletic Hall of Fame, 1985-1987 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 28)
  - Tennis Magazine's The Best in Tennis, 1987 November (Offsite-box 23, Folder 29)
  - BJK Commemorative stamp, 1988 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 30)
  - DC Certificate of Appreciation, 1988 May 19 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2, Item 9)
  - City of Long Beach California Proclamation for Hall of Fame induction, 1989 February 1 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - Gary, Indiana Proclamation and Honorary Citizen certificate, 1990 May 22 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 31)
  - The National Women's Hall of Fame induction certificate, 1990 August 26 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 2)
  - City of Schenectady, N.Y. BJK Week, 1995 July 15 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2, Item 4)
  - Cal State L.A. Honorary Doctorate of Humane Letters, 1997 June 14 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 32)
  - Hobart and William Smith College Elizabeth Blackwell Award, 1998 May 15 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 33)
  - United States Professional Tennis Association 25th Anniversary of Battle of the Sexes, 1998 September 20 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 2)
  - Trinity College Honorary Doctor of Humane Letters, 1998 November 6 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 34)
  - Tennis Week Great American Writing Awards, 1998 November 19 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2, Item 5)
  - University of Pennsylvania Honorary Doctor of Laws, 1999 May 17 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 35)
  - University of Pennsylvania Honorary Doctor of Laws [oversized], 1999 (Offsite-box 61, Folder 1)
  - Cal State L.A. BJK Sports Endowed Scholarship, 2002 May 29 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 36)
  - Cedar Crest College Honorary Doctor of Public Service (1 of 2 folders), 2002 October 24 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 37)
  - Cedar Crest College Honorary Doctor of Public Service (2 of 2 folders), 2002 October 24 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2, Item 6)
  - Dartmouth Honorary Doctor of Humane Letters (1 of 2 folders), 2003 June 8 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 38)
  - Dartmouth Honorary Doctor of Humane Letters (2 of 2 folders), 2003 June 8 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 3)
  - Women's Sports Foundation Appreciation Resolution, 2003 July 22 (Offsite-box 60, Folder 4)
  - Congressional Record proceedings in honor of BJK, 2004 April (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2, Item 7)
  - United States Professional Tennis Association, 2006-2011 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 39)
  - Huntington, N.Y. Special Proclamation to Ilana Kloss, 2006 April 30 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - USTA BJK National Tennis Center, 2006 August (Offsite-box 23, Folder 40)
  - US House of Representatives Certificate of Special Recognition, 2006 September 28 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 41)
  - USTA/ Middle States Tennis Hall of Fame, 2006 October 20 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 42)
  - California Hall of Fame, 2006 December (Offsite-box 23, Folder 43)
  - City of San Diego, CA BJK Day, 2007 August 18 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - Peabody Awards, 2007 June 4 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 3, Item 3)
    Program for the 66th Annual Peabody Awards Presentation Luncheon, at which the HBO Sports documentary Billie Jean King: Portrait of a Pioneer received a Peabody Award.
  - US House of Representatives Certificate of Special Recognition, 2007 October 6 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 44)
  - New York Stock Exchange closing bell, 2008 May 6 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 45)
  - Boston University Honorary Doctorate of Humane Letters (2 of 3 folders), 2008 May 18 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 46-47)
  - Boston University Honorary Doctorate of Humane Letters (1 of 3 folders), 2008 May 18 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 4)
  - Barnard College Medal of Distinction, 2008 May 20 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 48)
  - Presidential Medal of Freedom, 2009 August 12 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 3)
    Contains certificate.
  - City of Baton Rouge Honorary Mayor-President, 2009 December 8 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 5, Item 1)
    Honorary certificates for BJK and Sir Elton John.
  - Fed Cup Award of Excellence, 2010 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 4)
  - Presidential Proclamation of LGBT Pride Month, 2010 June (Offsite-box 25, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - Mill Valley, CA BJK Day, 2010 October 2 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 49)
  - University of Vermont Honorary Doctor of Letters, 2011 May 22 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 6)
  - Southern California Tennis Association Hall of Fame, 2011 August 5 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 50)
  - NY Women's Agenda Eleanor Guggenheimer Lifetime Achievement Award, 2011 December 6 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 51)
  - State of Pennsylvania certificate of recognition, 2013 April 10 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 52)
  - City of Philadelphia, PA John Binswanger Park Champion, 2013 May 16 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 7, Item 1-2)
  - Williams College Honorary Doctor of Laws, 2013 June 2 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 53)
  - City of New York BJK Day Proclamation, 2013 September 20 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 5)
  - Presidential Proclamation of National Physical Fitness and Sports Month, 2014-2015 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 7, Item 3-4)
  - Drexel University Doctor of Humane Letters, 2015 June 12 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 1)
  - Streb Lab for Action Mechanics Action Maverick Award, 2018 May 1 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 2)
    Award presented to BJK and Ilana Kloss.
  - NYC Pride Grand Marshal, 2018 June (Offsite-box 24, Folder 3)
  - LPAC Champion of Change Award, 2018 June 20 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 4)
  - National Museum of American History Great Americans, 2018 September 25 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 5)
  - ESPN Sports Humanitarian Awards, 2019 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 6)
  - Professional Tennis Registry certificate, undated (Offsite-box 24, Folder 7)
  - Honorary Paratrooper certificate, undated (Offsite-box 24, Folder 8)
  - Martin Luther King, Jr. National Memorial Project Foundation, undated (Offsite-box 25, Folder 8, Item 1)
  - TEDMED, undated (Offsite-box 25, Folder 8, Item 2)
  - Olympic Committee Women and Sport Achievement Diploma, undated (Offsite-box 25, Folder 8, Item 3)
  - United States Tennis Association, undated (Offsite-box 26, Folder 6)
- Series VI. Correspondence, 1952-2021; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Series VI includes letters, cards, and invitations sent to BJK by friends, colleagues, fans, and organizations. The correspondence reflects BJK's wide-ranging influence as a famed athlete, public figure, and advocate for women's equality, as well as her personal friendships and professional activities.
  Subseries VI.A. Alphabetical correspondence
  Subseries VI.B. Subject correspondence
  - Subseries VI.A. Alphabetical correspondence, 1952-2021; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    Subseries VI.A contains letters, cards, and invitations sent to BJK and organized individually by correspondent's last name. Contents of correspondence includes personal and professional topics. Particularly notable correspondents are identified within their respective folders or placed in a discrete folder when the amount of material justifies it. Regular correspondents of note include Bill and Hillary Clinton, Elton John, and Barack and Michelle Obama. Correspondence dates from 1952-2019.
    Arranged alphabetically followed by a file for unidentified correspondents.
    - A, 1966-2007 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 9)
      Notable correspondents include the All England Lawn Tennis & Croquet Club.
    - B, 1962-2015 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 10)
      Notable correspondents include George H.W. Bush and Warren Buffett.
    - Billboard Information Group, 1975 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 4)
      Includes Billboard Hot 100 chart for the week ending April 12, 1975 with Elton John's Philadelphia Freedom at number 1.
    - C (3 folders), 1960-2007 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 11-13)
      Notable correspondents include Sri Chinmoy.
    - Clinton, Bill and Hillary, 1993-2016 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 14)
      Contains two typed letters and handwritten note from William "Bill" Jefferson Clinton and several typed letters from Hillary Rodham Clinton. HRC's letters include personal condolences and official invitations and thanks for BJK's support of her Presidential campaign.
    - Clinton, President Bill, 2011-2012 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 6)
      Contains one letter addressed to BJK and Ilana Kloss and one letter addressed to BJK.
    - Clinton, Hillary, 2009-2019 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 7)
      Contains letters addressed to BJK and BJK and Ilana Kloss from 2009-2019 and 2012 holiday card. Also includes inserted photos from HBO "Dare to Compete" event.
    - D, 1965-2017 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 15)
      Notable correspondents include former Mayor of New York City David Dinkins.
    - E, 1990s-2006 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 16)
    - F, 2007-2019 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 17)
      Notable correspondents include the family of former President Gerald R. Ford.
    - G, 1959-2014 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 18)
      Notable correspondents include Senator Kirsten Gillibrand.
    - Ginsburg, Justice Ruth Bader, 2020 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 11)
      Contains outgoing letter from BJK to Justice Ginsburg inviting Justice Ginsburg to receive the WSF's BJK Leadership Award at the 2020 Annual Salute to Women in Sports and letter in response declining the award due to the U.S. judges Code of Conduct.
    - H, 1959-2018 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 19)
      Notable corespondents include Harvard Business School, photographer June Harrison, and the family of cartoonist Lee Holley.
    - I, 2007-2011 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 20)
      Contains correspondence from the International Tennis Hall of Fame.
    - J, 1963-2018 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 21)
      Notable corespondents include Perry T. Jones, President of the Southern California Tennis Association.
    - John, Elton, 2011 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 22)
      Contains letter thanking BJK and Ilana Kloss for gift sent to Elton John and David Furnish's son.
    - K, 1959-2019 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 23)
      Includes correspondence with Larry King from early in BJK's tennis career.
    - L, 1952-2007 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 24)
      Notable correspondents include the Long Beach Recreation Commission and Long Beach Polytechnic High School.
    - Los Cerritos fifth grade students, circa 2019 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 8)
    - M, 1959-2008 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 25)
    - N (2 folders), 1960s-2008 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 26-27)
      Notable correspondens include the New England Institute of Technology and Northeastern University Center for Sport in Society.
    - O, 1967-2011 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 28)
      Notable correspondence includes letter from Justice Sandra Day O'Connor.
    - Obama, Barack and Michelle (1 of 2), 2011-2016 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 29)
      Contains personal notes and official correspondence from Barack and Michelle Obama thanking and acknowleding BJK's work on the Obama re-election campaign and as a member of the President's Council on Fitness, Sports, & Nutrition.
    - Obama, Barack and Michelle (2 of 2), 2011-2010 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 9)
      Contains personal correspondence from President Barack and Michelle Obama to BJK and Ilana Kloss, including handwritten note and signed photograph from Michelle Obama sent to BJK after the US Open 2011, White House christmas cards from 2011 and 2014, and 2020 note congratulating BJK on the naming of the Billie Jean King Cup.
    - P, 1967-2013 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 30)
    - R (2 folders), 2004-2018 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 31-32)
    - Roberts, Rich, 1973 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 5)
      Contains correspondence from Rich Roberts of the Independent Press-Telegram with printed headline about the Moffitt family and Bobby Riggs during the Battle of the Sexes reporting.
    - S (2 folders), 1960s-2018 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 33-34)
      Notable correspondents include Maria Shriver and Justice Sonia Sotomayor.
    - T, 1961-2007 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 35)
    - U, 1959-2007 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 36)
      Contains correspondence from various United States Lawn Tennis Association staff and committee members informing BJK of her selection to the Wightman Cup team, ranking, and USTA Middle States Hall of Fame Induction Dinner.
    - V, 1967 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 37)
    - W, 1966-2019 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 38)
    - The White House, 1970-2017 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 39)
      Contains correspondence from The White House sent over various administrations, including a congratulatory letter for BJK's victories at Wimbledon from President Richard Nixon, Christmas cards from the Nixons, a note from Michelle Obama's Chief of Staff Tina Chen, and a letter from John DeStefano on behalf of President Trump ending BJK's appointment to the President's Council on Fitness, Sports, and Nutrition and thanking her for prior service.
    - Y, 1960s-2007 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 40)
    - Z, 2007 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 41)
    - Unidentified or unspecified correspondents, circa 1960s-2018 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 42)
      Contains letters, cards, and telegrams sent to BJK without a specified sender or with the sender's name incomplete or illegible.
    - Additional correspondence, 2017-2021 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 17)
      Contains additional notes, cards, and letters from various correspondents added to the collection after the initial donation. Notable correspondents are Warren Buffett, Venus Williams, and Janet Napolitano.
  - Subseries VI.B. Subject correspondence, 1962-2020; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    Subseries VI.B includes letters and cards from various correspondents grouped by subject or occassion. These groups were present when acquired and maintained in the processing of the collection.
    - Wimbledon telegrams, 1962 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 1)
      Contains a file of telegrams sent to BJK while competing at Wimbledon 1962, at which she and Karen Hantze were the women's double champions.
    - Fan mail and school reports (4 folders), 1973-2018 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 2-5)
      Contains a file of fan mail and notes sent to BJK, including school reports and essays written on and in honor of BJK. Correspondents include various teachers and their students, children from the Arthur Ashe Youth Tennis Center, and various fans inspired by BJK.
    - Postcards from South Africa, circa 2000s (Offsite-box 27, Folder 6)
      Contains unsent postcards and book of postcards from South Africa.
    - Holiday cards, 2001-2007 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 7)
      Contains a file of holiday greeting and photo cards from various senders.
    - Letters of condolence (18 folders), 2006 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 8-25)
      Contains letters of condolence and sympathy cards to BJK from various senders upon the death of her father, Bill Moffit. Includes printed emails with index of senders.
    - USTA Billie Jean King National Tennis Center naming (1 of 6 folders), 2006 August-September (Offsite-box 27, Folder 26)
      Contains a file of cards and letters sent to BJK in congratulations for the official naming of the "USTA Billie Jean King National Tennis Center" on the opening night of the 2006 U.S. Open, August 28.
    - USTA Billie Jean King National Tennis Center naming (5 of 6 folders), 2006 August-September (Offsite-box 28, Folder 1-5)
    - Oversized birthday and thank you cards, circa 2010s (Offsite-box 59, Folder 6)
    - Oversized thank you card, circa 2000s-2010s (Offsite-box 60, Folder 4)
    - Senator Birch Bayh tribute, 2019-2020 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 13)
- Series VII. Print matter, 1901-2020 (bulk, 1940-2020); 19 Linear feet in 14 record cartons, 4 flat boxes, and various oversize folders